Wesley W. Erickson

Wesley W. Erickson 2250 Patterson Street Eugene, OR 97405 USA +1-206-660-5811 wwe@uoregon.edu https://weserickson.com

Profile

Physics PhD with 6 years research experience specialized in stochastic processes, computational physics, and laser-cooled atoms. Experienced with exploratory numerical simulations and developing theoretical models, with knowledge of data analysis, statistics, and high performance computing.

Education

Ph.D. Physics, University of Oregon

September 2014 to June 2020

Dissertation: Lévy Motion and Laser Cooled Atoms Advisor: Prof. Daniel A. Steck

M.S. Physics, University of Oregon

September 2012 to June 2014

B.A. Physics, Reed College

September 2008 to June 2012

Thesis: Electromagnetically Induced Transparency Advisor: Prof. Lucas Illing

Experience

University of Oregon, Eugene, OR

Graduate Research Assistant

September 2014 to June 2020

- · Explored and modeled diffusion dynamics of laser-cooled atoms through simulations with Fortran, Python, Numba/CUDA.
- Studied conditioned Lévy processes and their relation to extreme events (see [1]).
- Developed feedback/control systems to perform release-recapture experiments on a single neutral Rb atom with Perl, C, Verilog.

Graduate Teaching Fellow / Graduate Employee

September 2012 to June 2020

- Delivered lectures, labs and tutorials; experience with both introductory and graduate level physics courses.
- Participated in course curriculum development (Physics of Sound and Music, Intro to Astronomy).

Additional Projects

COVID-19 Digital Polarization Collaboration (see [2])

September 2020 - present

- Wrote scripts for scraping COVID-19 related social media data with Python.
- Modeled time-dependence and correlations of various social media indicators.
- Developed metrics related to echo-chamber effects, topic polarization.

Cryptocurrency Trading Bots

January 2021 – present

· Developed, tested, and deployed custom trading algorithms on cryptocurrency exchanges, with Python/Cython, Docker.

Skills

Stochastic processes, Lévy Processes, Itō Calculus, First-hitting-time models, Monte Carlo methods, Statistics, Dynamical Systems, Time Series Analysis, Linux, Git, Docker, KVM Hypervisor, MPI, Profiling, Python, Julia, Fortran, Perl, Mathematica, C (embedded systems), Numba/CUDA.

Selected Publications and Presentations

- [1] Wesley W. Erickson and Daniel A. Steck, "The Anatomy of an Extreme Event: What Can We Infer About the History of a Heavy-Tailed Random Walk?", *submitted for publication (preprint available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.03849)*, (2020).
- [2] Jun Lang, Wesley W. Erickson, Zhuo Jing-Schmidt, "#MaskOn! #MaskOff! Digital polarization of mask-wearing in the United States during COVID-19", *submitted for publication*, (2021).
- [3] Wesley W. Erickson and Daniel A. Steck, "Lévy Dynamics of Single Laser-Cooled Atoms," 51st Annual Meeting of the APS Division of Atomic, Molecular and Optical Physics, June 1–5, 2020. Portland, OR, USA. Talk abstract: https://meetings.aps.org/Meeting/DAMOP20/Session/J09.3
- [4] Richard V. Wagner, Wesley W. Erickson, and Daniel A. Steck. "In situ sensing of position and temperature of a single trapped atom via resonance fluorescence." *48th Annual Meeting of the APS Division of Atomic, Molecular and Optical Physics*, June 5–9, 2017. Sacramento, CA, USA. Poster abstract: https://meetings.aps.org/link/BAPS.2017.DAMOP.Q1.68